Hi Guys next list is my next project knowledge and dismissed sound as trivial but it is very important.
In fact I have seen that a lot of students especially those who are looking at that particular information
for PMP Exam tend to ignore these specific chapters and sections in the Pinback guide.
So you shouldn't do that.
These are very important.
A lot of questions may directly come from these sections or sometimes you may get a sense of you and
then you a certain question which would be related to these.
So it's very important to pay attention to all these sections of managed project knowledge is basically
nothing else than managing the knowledge.
And when you say knowledge it's you are going to use the existing knowledge.
So all the documents which you have organization and process assets all of that will be your seed will
be initiating point for your document analysis and from there as you progress as you progress with the
project you'll create more knowledge and that is huge really.
I mean everything is captured in the form of documents.
So you as a project manager are responsible for making sure that all the knowledge and all the information
is very documented and captured because that will become part of your seed information knowledge for
the next project.
So it's very important to manage that knowledge in a project.
And this has performed throughout the project so it's not like you're doing it at some particular stage
like we have seen a lot of processes earlier.
But here you have to perform this process throughout the project.
And this is the input output diagram so you can see as far as input is concerned we have our project
management plan all the components anything and everything will be part of a knowledge management because
potentially you are looking at the documents information.
So any piece of information is vital here.
So all the project management plan I mean all the components and the documents and the lessons learned
register which is maintained for all the products so when you start a project you will have just register
the information for the previous project.
Then you have predicted assignment to break down structures so selection criteria is stakeholder register
deliverable and environmental factors and organizational processes.
All of that really serve the purpose of the in part here as far as tools and techniques expert judgment
is one of the most common tools and techniques in the entire field of project management that's going
to be there.
Then you have knowledge management information management which is going the way you classify and document
knowledge into personnel and teams because active learning facilitation leadership networking political
awareness and political awareness is very important.
I mean as soon as you know you are dealing with human you are dealing with politics.
So it's very important to see to have this awareness.
You need to know what kind of information is important for the project what kind of information is not
important for the project.
Sometimes you may get some information which may look or sound trivial but that may end up you know
affecting your entire project because let's say senior management wasn't favoring that project.
You got the go ahead initially but later on you know something changed and the project was disapproved
which really you.
And all your efforts were wasted.
So that's why it's very important to keep an eye on the political surroundings and networking leadership
already you know part of that.
And as you will receive a lesson learned or just as input you are going to produce one.
So that is going to be out.
Then you have project management plan.
It's an organizational process a so you make the project management plan any documentation you create
really be regarded as organizational process.
So let's say you've started to use a scrum and now you really create something for backlog product backlog.
So that will serve the purpose of a template for research and for other projects that will be out.
And these are the applications which basically means that are this is used.
So this activity is used in updating the project management plan project documents and organizational
process assets.
So that's it for this.
But as I have mentioned earlier ignored these sections these are very small quick but they will give
you lot of vital information about how a project operates within the organization.
Thank you.